bioone.org 2019-12-14

# BioOne Privacy Policy

BioOne is committed to protecting the privacy of the users of its website. To inform you of our policy concerning user privacy, we have adopted the following guidelines, which are intended to adhere to the [Privacy Shield Framework](https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome) published by the U.S. Department of Commerce and to the General Data Protection Regulation ([GDPR](https://www.eugdpr.org/)). Please note that these guidelines are subject to change, and any such changes will be included on this page and shall become effective upon their posting on our website. (See "Changes to Policy" below.) 

### Information BioOne Collects

The personal information BioOne collects will depend on how you are using the BioOne website. To enable your access to the BioOne website through your library or institution, we may collect information concerning the institution's Internet protocol address or other authentication methods. We may also collect certain non-personally identifiable information, such as the type of browser you are using, the type of operating system you are using, and the domain name of your Internet Service Provider. To facilitate your pay-per-view order, we collect your name, postal address, email address, credit card details and transactional information. To create a My BioOne account, we collect your name, email address, and password, as well as other information you may fill in. In addition, we may collect personally identifiable information through correspondence you send to us. Unless you provide us with personally identifiable information, you remain anonymous to us other than by association with an Internet protocol address or other authentication mechanism.

### Security of Information and Personal Data

BioOne is committed to protecting the security of your personal data. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal data from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. For example, we store the personal data you provide on computer systems that have limited access and are in controlled facilities. When we transmit highly confidential data (such as a credit card number or password) over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption.

Our websites have security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. We have taken the necessary steps to provide a secure server for transmission of sensitive data to and from our websites. We encrypt all payment data including your credit card number transmitted through our secure web server so no one else can read it.

### Use of the Information

We use the personal information collected in ways that are compatible with the purposes for which it was intended to be used: to enable your use of BioOne; to facilitate pay-per-view; to create your My BioOne account; to create your BioOne Career Center profile; to respond to your inquiries; for system administration, customer support, and troubleshooting purposes; for targeted marketing and product service announcements; for sending newsletters (also directed at institutional participation in BioOne); to improve the design of our website; to enable us to enforce our [Terms of Use](https://bioone.org/terms-of-use); and in aggregate form, to track and analyze site usage. BioOne will take reasonable steps to ensure that personal information is relevant to its intended use, accurate, complete, and current. 

### Use of Cookies

BioOne employs "cookie technology". Cookies are small pieces of text that are stored on your computer and act as a tool for controlling certain system variables and storing system configuration information in the WWW environment. BioOne uses cookies to store user preferences for viewing and printing and to store authentication information. No personal information is extracted in the cookie setting process, and we do not use cookies to identify other sites or pages you have visited. We do not involve advertisers, who may place a cookie on your browser, in the operation of our site. 

### Onward Transfer of Information

BioOne may work with other organizations that provide specific services for us, such as credit card processing. BioOne's credit card processors comply with the Payment Card Industry (PCI) Data Security Standard. We will only share personal information to the extent necessary for the third party to provide these services for us, and these third parties are prohibited from using personal information provided by BioOne for any other purpose.

Except in the following special circumstances, BioOne does not sell or share personal information about or the purchasing history of individual users:

  * If required to do so by law or if we believe in good faith that such action is necessary to comply with the law or a legal proceeding, to protect against violations of our Terms and Conditions of Use, or to protect and defend our rights and property or the rights and property of publishers selling content through the service;
  * With service providers with whom we have entered into agreements to assist us with our business operations; or,
  * Other third parties if necessary to deliver our services, such as an institution with which you are affiliated.

In addition, BioOne shares general usage data in aggregated form so that no personal information is identifiable to participating libraries, publishers, and the general public. BioOne will provide all of your retained personal information entered at registration (where applicable) on request.

### Links to Other Sites

Our site contains external links to other organizations and websites, and we do not control the use of data collection on external websites. We encourage you to read their privacy policies and terms of use. This privacy policy governs only the BioOne site.

### Your Consent

When creating an account on our website, you must consent to the collection and use, in accordance with this policy, of the information you provide to us. Users who supply us with their telephone numbers will only receive telephone contact from us if there is a problem regarding a pay-per-view purchase. Library administrators who provide telephone numbers will only be contacted in connection with BioOne Complete.

### Withdrawing Your Consent

You can withdraw your consent to receive marketing email or postal mail at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of email sent by BioOne, [contacting us](mailto:helpdesk@BioOne.org), or selecting your communication preferences in your BioOne account.

### Right to Be Forgotten

We may be required to archive your personal information; however, we will not retain personal data for longer than is necessary for the purpose that it was obtained. You have the right to request that we delete your personal information in certain circumstances, i.e., where the purpose for collecting your personal information no longer exists and we are not obligated by legal reasons to retain all or any part of your personal information.

### Suppression Lists

We will not contact you about our related products or services or send you any other communications if you have indicated that you do not want to receive these communications. In this case, your name will be included in appropriate suppression lists.

### Changes to Policy

We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time. Any material changes in the way we collect, use, and/or share your personally identifiable information will be posted on-line and reflected in the "Last Updated" reference below. You are bound by such revisions and should therefore visit the page to review the current terms from time to time.

### Subject Access Rights

You have the right to obtain a copy of all personal information we hold about you. To request this information, you must submit a written request to [helpdesk@BioOne.org](mailto:helpdesk@BioOne.org).

### Right to Request a Correction

You can request that we correct or update your personal data at any time to ensure that your information is accurate and up-to-date. To request corrections, you may either log in to your BioOne account to make the changes, or submit a written request to [helpdesk@BioOne.org](mailto:helpdesk@BioOne.org).

### Data Portability

You can request that your personal data be transferred directly to another "data controller" at any time. To request this information, you must submit a written request to [helpdesk@BioOne.org](mailto:helpdesk@BioOne.org).

### Dispute Resolution and Enforcement

We engage in periodic self-assessment to ensure compliance with our Privacy Policy and to confirm that the policy remains accurate, comprehensive for the information intended to be covered, prominently displayed, completely implemented, and in conformity with the Privacy Shield Framework and GDPR. We encourage interested persons to raise any concerns with us using the contact information below. We will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of personal information in accordance with the principles contained in this policy. If you have any inquiries about this Privacy Policy or its implementation, you may [contact us](mailto:susan@bioone.org). Your use of this site is also governed by our [Terms of Use](https://bioone.org/terms-of-use) statement. We encourage you to please read that as well. 

_Last updated, May 25, 2018_
